Jeannie Yamakawa

Developer, Designer & Strategist

<u>linkedin.com/in/jeannieyamakawa</u> <u>github.com/JeannieYamakawa</u> <u>www.JeannieYamakawa.com</u> Austin, TX (210) 549-6331 jkyamakawa@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Strategist with design & dev chops. Has a flair for creative solutions and 11+ years of experience in business, research, design, code, and communications. Looking for opportunities to problem-solve with a collaborative team.

Skills

Design

- Prototyping & Wireframes
- Adobe Photoshop / Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML / CSS
- User Stories & Epics
- Branding & Logo Design
- Information Architecture

Development

- JavaScript / ES6 / Node.js
- C# / .NET / VisualStudio
- Version Control (GitHub)
- AngularJS / ¡Query / Semantic UI
- PostgreSQL / Oracle / MongoDB
- XML / XSLT
- Ruby on Rails

General

- Agile / Scrum / Kanban (JIRA / PivotalTracker / Trello)
- Technical Documentation
- CMS (Wordpress) / CRM (Salesforce)
- Email Marketing & Campaigns
- Mac / Windows / Google / Outlook
- Team & Resource Management

Experience

» Full Stack Engineer | Cox Automotive - vAuto (Contract)

Apr, 2017 - Current

Austin, TX

- -Scraped & transformed features from international automotive websites, expanding product team's data sets by hundreds of automotive dealers and providers.
- -Took initiative to write training documents for future devs on integrations team.

» Marketing Consultant | FabulousFit

Feb, 2017 - Current

Austin, TX

- -Eliminated monthly cost of maintaining >11,000 non-active accounts on previously-overlapping mailing lists by reorganizing campaigns based on past user conversions, metrics, and trends.
- -Increased subscriber enrollment by up to 150% monthly by restructuring architecture of information on website to redefine clearer division between subscriber and non-subscriber content.

» Full Stack Engineer | SandBox Commerce (Contract)

2016 - 2017

Austin, TX

- -Built new admin console, elevating SandBox Commerce from pen/paper records and word-of-mouth to 100% automated calculations and digital enrollment.
- -Overhauled lead generation and business conversions calculations with a new custom API and new public-facing AngularJS website design.

» Project Lead & Full Stack Engineer | Digital Rolodex

2016

Austin, TX

- -Led a team of six engineers to develop a mobile Google Play app + web portal. Team completed first iteration MVP with leftover time and reached several additional stretch goals.
- » Designer & Photographer | Self-Employed / Freelance

2009 - Current

Austin, TX

- -Streamlined workflow in creation, polishing, and coordinating of thousands of files, designs, and pieces of information, including hiring and training contractors to increase productivity.
- -Fulfilled client needs to build diverse portfolio of creative work (including web design, graphic design, photography & video), establishing returning business relationships.

Other Related Experience

» AngularJS Full Stack Engineer | Sprintr (Personal Project)

2016

Austin, TX

- -Built a multi-player Google Chrome extension & web app that tracks user productivity as a competitive game with a team of three engineers, utilizing graphed data displays from newly-constructed API.
- » Communications Director | Hawaii State Senate--Office of Majority

2008

Honolulu, HI

- -Garnered state & national news coverage (e.g. NY Times) for initiatives by connecting with print & A/V journalists.
- -Formulated and published all Senate Majority online content in the 2008 session, including many official senatorial statements, as well as delivering press releases, statements, and photos for print media.
- » Staff Writer, Copy Editor, Photographer | Ka Leo O Hawai'i

2007

Honolulu, HI

- -Acted as departmental liaison for University of Hawaii's newspaper, delivering content, visuals, and editing services.
- -Planned content of future issues in press-room meetings for consumption of more than 10,000 readers.

Education

- » Full Stack Certification
- » B.A. Media & Photography, Art Minor

Galvanize, 2017 University of Hawaii, 2007